Oscar Castillejo

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/oscar-castillejo/ Email: oscar.castillejo.sa@gmail.com

Github: https://github.com/oacs Mobile: +1-647-615-3226

Summary

Senior Software Developer(5+ years) with a strong background in Web development using technologies such as Typescript, React.js (Redux), and AWS. As a recent Technical Lead at Finastra, I successfully led a team of 10 developers in disrupting the Canadian mortgage industry, and was recognized 9 times for outstanding performance. Prior to that, I was a founding software engineer at Doorr, where I contributed to raising \$\frac{3}{2}\$1 million in Series A seed funding and promptly addressed client-facing issues. Holds a Computer Science degree. Seeking a challenging role as a Frontend developer.

EDUCATION

Universidad Católica Andrés Bello

Guayana, VE

 $Computer\ Science$

Aug 2015 - Dec 2020

SKILLS SUMMARY

• Languages: Typescript, Javascript, PostgreSQL, MySQL, DynamoDB, GraphQL, Java, Go, SASS, CSS

- Framework & Libraries: Express.js, Node.js, React.js (Redux), Vue.js (Vuex), TailwindCSS, Apollo, Rxjs
- Tools: AWS, Git, Docker, Jest, Cypress, Webpack, Jira, Confluence, Figma

EXPERIENCE

Finastra Mississauga, CA

Software Engineer Technical Lead

May 2022 - Feb 2023

- Technical desicion making: Led an international team of 10 developers to disrupt the Canadian mortgage industry taking care of code reviews, splitting efforts, design improvements and promoting quality code of 3 products
- Directing the Release Process: Directed the release process with live support of 7 major features for the Expert Proproduct and more than 20 hotfixes and small enhancements
- Core Feature Designer: Redesigned key workflows, resulting in a 25% increase in productivity (measured by decreased time to completion) and a streamlined, user-friendly experience. Worked with Product Owners to optimize workflows based on requirements.
- AWS Services Expertise: Frequently use various AWS services (RDS, DynamoDB, Api Gateway, SQS, Lamda, S3, CloudWatch)
- **Development Internship Program Director**: Designed and Directed our development internship program. This included: interviewing potential candidates; leading a team of interns to improve a web client, API, infrastructure and CI/CD; and work with project managers and stakeholders to ensure timely delivery
- Recognized for Outstanding Performance: Awarded 9 times within the organization for innovation, leading the team to success, outstanding performance and manage to solve critical situations on vacations

Doorr, adquired by Finastra

Mississauga, CA

Founding Software Engineer

Aug 2020 - May 2022

- o Library Compatibility Manager: Ensured dependencies and libraries were compatible and up to date with latest releases avoiding more than 120 vulnerabilities on the products
- Startup Contributor: One of three Back-end engineer at a startup that raised \$1 million in Series A seed funding design the foundations of core features such as CRM, Automations, External API, Websockets for real time updates and (i18n) solution on a full-stack perspective and always bringing ideas on how to improve all the process on the company
- **Production Code Fixer**: Promptly addressed client-facing issues reported by the Customer Success team delivering hotfixes to increase customers satisfaction on quick response times

Telesero United States
Frontend Developer Aug 2019 - Mar 2020

• Legacy Code Migration Specialist: Migrated legacy code to technologies such as React, Redux, improving the performance of the system with lower response time from 5 seconds to 1 second of load time

- Dashboard and Monitor Web App Designer: Designed a Dashboard and Monitor web app from scratch with real-time updates using Websocket and Rxjs, enhancing data representation through the implementation of interactive charts and graphs
- Material Design Implementation Specialist: Revamped the look and feel of the company's following the Material Design Patterns using Styled components, resulting in overall better UI/UX Improved user satisfaction by 90% with the implementation of intuitive navigation and better visual design elements

Pintosoft Venezuela Venezuela

Lead Web Developer

 $Jul\ 2018$ - $Mar\ 2019$

 Crypto Gaming Web App Designer: Design web apps to motivate the usage of the company crypto currency with games and gambling features